Full Version - Curriculum Vitae Jose Luis L.J. Silva

I am a PhD candidate in Physics at Uppsala University working with computational physics. In my thesis, I worked with simulations of materials for hydrogen production. This project is jointly a theory-experiment effort for the development of new operando spectroscopy techniques to probe solid-liquid interfaces. I have daily experience with programming languages such as Python, ShellScript, C/C++ and Matlab. I have also experience with Multi-scale simulations using different packages - (Molecular Dynamics in Gromacs, Monte Carlo Dynamics, VASP, Quantum Espresso, Gaussian 09 and Jaguar). I am passionate about algorithm development and optimization techniques. I have been also exploring applications of Aritifial Intelligence, Machine Learning and Deep Learning into differente fields. This curiosity led me to experience working as Research Engineer within Machine Learning and Reinforcement Learning techniques at Veoneer (Computer Vision team) for self-driving cars. The topic of my research was entitled: Tracking multiple targets using Reinforcement Learning Techniques: LSTM and Markov Decision Processes.



Personal Information

Full name: Jose Luis Lima de Jesus Silva

Address: Lägerhyddsvägen 1, 752 37 Uppsala

Personal Website: https://jseluis.github.io

https://jseluis.com

Contact: jseluis.silva@gmail.com

jose.silva@physics.uu.se

Phone number: +46 72-019 90 52

Formal Education

2016 - June 2020 Ph.D in Physics

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

Position: Ph.D Student in Physics regarding Energy Materials.

Employment: Department of Physics and Astronomy, Division of Materials Theory

2016 - 2019 Licenciate of Philosophy in Physics

Specialization in Atomic, Molecular, Condensed Matter Physics

Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden

Employment: Department of Physics and Astronomy, Division of Materials Theory

2013 - 2015

Master of Science in Physics

Federal University of Bahia, UFBA, Salvador, Brazil

Dissertation title: Absorption effects of photocatalysts on (110) Rutile TiO2 surface using

Advisor: Denis Gilbert Francis David

Scholarship: Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES)

Bachelor of Science in Physics

 $Federal\ University\ of\ Bahia,\ UFBA,\ Salvador,\ Brazil$

Scholarship: Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (Cnpq)

Professional Experience in Research and Teaching

2018 – 2019 Position: Teaching Assistant; Department: Physics and Astronomy

Course: Mekanik Baskurs

2019 - 2019

Position: Research Engineer Summer Intern; Company: Veoneer

Research: Tracking multiple targets using Reinforcement Learning Techniques:

LSTM and Markov Decision Processes

2013 - 2015

Position: Assistant Teacher at Federal University of Bahia

Position: Assistant Teacher at Devry University

Department: Earth and the environment Physics

Schemes of job: Temporary **Contract hours:** 20 hours/week

Courses: General and Experimental Physics I (Mechanics), General and Experimental Physics II (Oscilations, Waves and Thermodynamics) and

Mechanics of Materials I, II.

2012 - 2015 Position: Master in Physics

Group: LaPO (Laboratory of Optical Properties)

Schemes of job: Full-time

Scholarship: Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel (CAPES)

2011 - 2012 Position: Junior Technological Research

Schemes of job: Full-time

Project: Modeling and fractal characterization of invasion fronts in petroleum reservoirs.

Contract hours: 20 hours/week

Scholarship: National Council for Scientific and Technological Development (CNPq)

2010 - 2011 Contract: Junior Scientific Research

Group: SICLAM (Computational Simulation of Liquids and Molecular aggregates)

Schemes of job: Full-time

Project: Computer Simulation of Molecular Nanostructures and Extended Systems.

Contract hours: 20 hours/week

Scholarship: National Council for Scientific and Technological Development (CNPq)

2010 - 2010 Contract: Junior Scientific Research

Group: SICLAM (Computational Simulation of Liquids and Molecular aggregates)

Schemes of job: Full-time

Project: Study of magnetic properties in paramagnetic aggregates using

first principles calculations. **Contract hours:** 20 hours/week

ICTP-SAIFR, UNESP, São Paulo, Brazil

Scholarship: National Council for Scientific and Technological Development (CNPq)

Complementary Education/Schools and Events

2018 – 2018	CoTXS meeting in theoretical spectroscopy Seminar: XPS - spectroscopy of Ru complex in aqueous environment Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden
2017 – 2017	Introduction to Data Science, 2017 Uppsala University, Uppsala, Sweden
2017 – 2017	Certificate Fundamentals and Applications of Heterogeneous Catalysis, SUNCAT Summer Institute 2017 – Presentation of "Nanodevices as micro-reactors for studying hydrogen evolution reaction" Stanford University, California, USA
2016 – 2016	Certificate from College on Multiscale Computational Modeling of Materials for Energy Applications. ICTP, Trieste, Italy
2016 - 2016	Certification in High Performance Computing, PDC Summer School. KTH, Stockholm, Sweden
2016 - 2016	CAPES-Stint Second Workshop Seminar: Theoretical x-ray spectroscopy of redox reactions: The case of Ru Complexes electrocatalysts Natal, RN, Brazil
2014 - 2014	Certificate of School on Electronic Structure and Quantum Transport Methods.

2012 – 2012	Short Term Course Certificate in lons and electron accelerators. Federal University of Bahia, UFBA, Salvador, Brazil
2012 - 2012	Short Term Course Certificate in DFT semiconductor materials study. Federal University of Bahia, UFBA, Salvador, Brazil
2012 - 2012	Short Term Course Certificate in Thin Films applied to solar energy. Federal University of Bahia, UFBA, Salvador, Brazil
2012 - 2012	Short Term Course Certificate in Molecular Orbital Theory. Federal University of Bahia, UFBA, Salvador, Brazil
2012 - 2012	Short Term Course Certificate in Topics in Field Theory. Federal University of Bahia, UFBA, Salvador, Brazil
2011 - 2011	Short Term Course Certificate in Solar Energy. Federal University of Bahia, UFBA, Salvador, Brazil
2011 - 2011	Winter School in Medical Physics. São Paulo University, USP, São Paulo, Brazil
2011 - 2011	VI EVFITA Physics Summer School. Seminar: Study of magnetic properties in paramagnetic aggregates using first principles calculations. Aeronautics Institute of Technology ITA, São Jose Dos Campos, Brazil

Recent Projects:

Jsneural Networks in Python from scratch

https://github.com/jseluis/deep_learning/

This is an open-source project for learning how to build Deep Neural Networks using Stochastic Gradient Descent from scratch.

Autonomous Vehicles, Computer Vision, Optimization, Deep Learning, Autonomous Systems and more ... https://github.com/jseluis/

Series of open-source pipelines to explore applications of Computer Vision and Deep Learning for self-driving vehicles.

Aicavity "Learn By Doing"

https://aicavity.com

Platform with online training and tutorials in Coding and Engineering, including recent Techniques of Machine Learning, Deep Learning and Artificial Intelligence. The platform Provides free courses through an Youtube Channel:

https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC94TU0rgoBsvLldMxalP8oQ
(Portuguese and English)

Personal Website

https://jseluis.com

Here you can find a list of projects, publications, conferences, GitHub repositories and more informations about what I have been doing in my career.

Author: Jose Luis Silva, Silva, J.L

Publication List

Silva, J.L., Unger, I., Matias, T., Franco, L., Damas, G.B., Costa, L.T., Toledo, K.C.F., Rocha, T.C.R., Saak, C.M., Coutinho, K., Araki, K., Björneholm, O., Brena, B. and Araujo, C.M., 2019.
 X-ray Photoelectron Fingerprints of High-Valent Ruthenium-Oxo Complexes Along the Oxidation Reaction Pathway in Aqueous Environment. The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters

https://pubs.acs.org/doi/abs/10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b02756

- Silva, J.L., Brena, B. and Araujo, C.M., 2020. g-C₃N₄/WTe₂ hybrid electrocatalyst for efficient hydrogen evolution reaction. The Journal of Physical Chemistry C https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jpcc.9b11982
- Zhou, Y., Silva, J.L., Woods, J.M., Pondick, J.V., Feng, Q., Liang, Z., Liu, W., Lin, L., Deng, B., Brena, B., Xia, F., Peng, H., Liu, Z., Wang, H., Araujo, C.M. and Cha, J.J., 2018.
 Revealing the contribution of individual factors to hydrogen evolution reaction catalytic activity. Advanced Materials, 30(18), p.1706076. https://doi.org/10.1002/adma.201706076
- Zhou, Y., Pondick, J.V., Silva, J.L., Woods, J.M., Hynek, D.J., Matthews, G., Shen, X., Feng, Q., Liu, W., Lu, Z., Liang, Z., Brena, B., Cai, Z., Wu, M., Jiao, L., Hu, S., Wang, H., Araujo, C.M. and Cha, J.J., 2019. Unveiling the Interfacial Effects for Enhanced Hydrogen Evolution Reaction on MoS2/WTe2 Hybrid Structures. Small, 15(19), p.1900078. https://doi.org/10.1002/smll.201900078
- Lanzilotto, V., Silva, J.L., Zhang, T., Stredansky, M., Grazioli, C., Simonov, K., Giangrisostomi, E., Ovsyannikov, R., De Simone, M., Coreno, M., Araujo, C.M., Brena, B. and Puglia, C., 2018. Spectroscopic Fingerprints of Intermolecular H-Bonding Interactions in Carbon Nitride Model Compounds. Chemistry—A European Journal, 24(53), pp.14198-14206. https://doi.org/10.1002/chem.201802435
- Pavliuk, M.V., Gutiérrez Álvarez, S., Hattori, Y., Messing, M.E., Czapla-Masztafiak, J., Szlachetko, J., Silva, J.L., Araujo, C.M., A. Fernandes, D.L., Lu, L., Kiely, C.J., et al., 2019. Hydrated Electron Generation by Excitation of Copper Localized Surface Plasmon Resonance. The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters, 10(8), pp.1743-1749. https://pubs.acs.org/doi/10.1021/acs.jpclett.9b00792